WILLIAM WARNER

Memphis, TN | 901-292-6465 | will.r.warner@gmail.com | willrwarner.com

Professional Summary

An aspiring Web Developer with 8 years of professional experience in the Mechanical Engineering field with involvement in mechanical design, project management, and field support across multiple industries. Skilled at working in teams and utilizing problem solving and time management abilities to deliver results in a safe, timely, and effective manner. Seeking a full-time position that will utilize and grow my programming skills.

Related Skills

- Competent in HTML 5, CSS 3, and Javascript
- Exposure to Visual Basics for Applications, C, C++, Java, and Python
- Knowledge of utilizing a web hosting service to host a static webpage

Education

Tech901 - Web Programming

April 2019

- Created websites using HTML 5, CSS 3, and Javascript
- Debugged javascript programs and websites using Google Chrome developer tools
- Wrote code using VSCode and Atom IDEs
- Utilized version control with Git and GitHub

Mississippi State University - Bachelor of Science - Mechanical Engineering Overall GPA: 4.0

December 2012

Experience

Project Engineer - Diversified Conveyors, Intl. - Memphis, TN

2016 - Present

- Performed as Lead Engineer and oversaw 5 junior engineers on a \$400 million project
- Worked with structural engineering firms to ensure adequate and compatible structural designs
- Coordinated with Project Management to ensure deliverables were completed on time and in accordance with the contract specifications and applicable codes
- Developed new drafting techniques to improve coordination with external vendors

Design Engineer - Chevron Corporation - Richmond, CA

2013-2016

- Performed as Lead Engineer and supervised junior engineers for 2 plant outages with a total expenditure of \$23 million
- Optimized work scope on a project to reduce installation costs by \$20,000
- Worked with Materials Engineers to specify material requirements for equipment
- Analyzed inspections and test data with Inspectors and Technicians to develop repair plans

Reliability Intern - Valero Energy Corporation - Memphis, TN

Summer 2012

- Worked with senior engineers to develop plans for refinery equipment upgrades
- Developed a database for tracking refinery equipment

Engineering Co-op - Hunter Engineering Co. - Durant, MS

2010-2011

- Worked with senior engineers on quality control issues and factory upgrades
- Created a database for quality control inspection equipment
- Determined root causes of manufacturing issues and developed solutions to these issues